Guide to the Records of American Association for Ethiopian Jews (AAEJ), undated, 1960-1961, 1963, 1965-1968, 1970-1995, 2001-2002 *I-503
American Jewish Historical Society, Boston, MA and New York, NY
- Subgroup III: Ethiopian Jewry - Secondary Articles, undated, 1960, 1965, 1967-1968, 1971, 1973-1993, 1995; Boxes 140-167.
  - Series C: Falashas/Ethiopian Jews Newspaper Clippings, undated, 1977-1991; Boxes 147-151.
    - "Rabbis Embrace Falasha Community," Israel Today, February 16-29, 1979 (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - "A Cry for Jewish Education," Israel Today, June 7, 1979 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - "Important dates in Falasha History," Keeping Posted, circa 1980 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Ethiopian Jews, first list, 1981 (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - Ethiopian Jews, second list, undated (Box 151, Folder 9)
    - "'Silence' on Falashas Deplored," Detroit Jewish News, April 23, 1982; "Falashas now in Israel feel powerless and abandoned," Sentinel, April 29, 1982 (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - "Story on Ethiopian Jews Paints a False Picture," The Jewish Post, September 23, 1982 (Box 151, Folder 11)
    - "The Falasha Game," Compass, Fall 1982 (Box 151, Folder 12)
    - City of Chicago Resolution, January 7, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 13)
    - "Tales of the Midrash and Talmud…," by Sholom B'Moshe, Jewish Press, January 14, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 14)
    - "Falashas reported to be living well in Ethiopia," The Jerusalem Post International Edition, January 23-29, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 15)
    - "Why doesn't Israel do something about the Ethiopian Jews?," Sentinel, March 24, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 16)
    - "Israel consul general 'very distressed' to read student essay about Falashas," Sentinel, April 14, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 17)
    - "Dying Ethiopian Jews," by Simcha Jacobovici, New York Times, April 23, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 18)
    - "Black Jews: A Struggle to Survive," Israel Today, September 8, 1983; "Feed Ethiopia Fast," New York Times, August 28, 1983 (Box 151, Folder 19)
    - Film Information, undated, 1984 (Box 151, Folder 20)
    - "World stands silent as Ethiopian Jews die," Star and Tribune, 1984 (Box 151, Folder 21)
    - "Falasha Update", February 1984 (Box 151, Folder 22)
    - "Special Interview: The Falashas: An Endangered People," JTA Daily News Bulletin, March 12, 1984 (Box 151, Folder 23)
    - "Dying in camps, Black Jew cries," The Jewish Chronicle, March 29, 1984 (Box 151, Folder 24)
    - "Clothing needed for Falashas", June 1984 (Box 151, Folder 25)
    - The Jerusalem Post: "Meddling not needed," June 24, 1984; "Information drive to begin about Ethiopian immigrants," June 26, 1984; "Ethiopian Solidarity Week kicks off," June 25, 1984; "Helping the Falashas," June 20, 1984; "Solidarity with Ethiopian Jews a secret," June 26, 1984 (Box 151, Folder 26)
    - Absorption, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 27)
    - "In the running," Israel Scene, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 28)
    - Operation Moses: Articles and responses, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 29)
    - Protests, undated, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 30)
    - "Disease, Not Starvation Threatens Gondar's Falashas," The Jewish Advocate, December 6, 1984; "2,000 Jews Die in Sudan Camps for Ethiopians," New York Times, January 20, 1985, 1984-1985 (Box 151, Folder 31)
    - "Senators' secret bid to aid Ethiopian Jews disclosed," Jewish Week, March 25, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 32)
    - "Strangers No More," New York Times, March 26, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 33)
    - "And Dan Shall Judge His People," Hamevaser, April 1985 (Box 151, Folder 34)
    - "Rescuers reunited with Ethiopians in Herzliya," Jerusalem Post, April 12, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 35)
    - "Ethiopian odyssey: One couple's perilous journey to save Africa's Ethiopian Jews," Streets, April 21-27, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 36)
    - "Operation Moses," Jewish Week, October 25, 1985; "Return to Ethiopia," Sentinel, October 1985 (Box 151, Folder 37)
    - "Strengthen the sustainers and changers!," Sentinel, October 10, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 38)
    - Teda Health Clinic, Sentinel, October 17, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 39)
    - "Sudan moves again to block departure of more Ethiopian Jews," London JTA, December 6, 1985 (Box 151, Folder 40)
    - Film "Falasha: Exile of the Black Jews", undated (Box 151, Folder 41)
    - "Na'amat and the Ethiopian Jews," Pioneer Woman, undated (Box 151, Folder 42)
    - New York Resolution, undated (Box 151, Folder 43)
    - Postcards to Prime Minister in Israel, undated (Box 151, Folder 44)
    - Postcards to Wisconsin group, undated (Box 151, Folder 45)
  - Series D: Ethiopian Jewry Press Clippings, undated, 1986-1990; Box 152, Folders 1-7.
    The series is composed of press clippings pertaining to Ethiopian Jewry dating from 1986 to 1990. At the end of the series are additional pamphlets and articles pertaining to the Ethiopian Jews.
    - Press Clippings, 1986 (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Press Clippings, 1987 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    - Press Clippings, 1988 (Box 152, Folder 3)
    - Press Clippings, 1989 (Box 152, Folder 4)
    - Press Clippings, 1990 (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Press Clippings, undated (Box 152, Folder 6)
    - Press Clippings, Pamphlets and Articles, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 152, Folder 7)
  - Series E: Ethiopian Jewry Subject Files, undated, 1979, 1981-1993, 1995; Box 152, Folder 8 -- Box 157.
    Susan Pollack worked as an activist on behalf of AAEJ from 1985 to 1993. In 1983, Pollack took a secret mission to Ethiopia to distribute six cases of medicine. Despite the war, she was able to get six large boxes past the authorities and into the villages. In Gondar, she was met by an Ethiopian Jew working for the AAEJ. After delivering the medicines, she learned about Ethiopian Jewish customs, lifestyles and problems. Susan became "hooked" and secretly passed money to Ethiopian Jews preparing to leave. She mastered techniques for dealing with suspicious bureaucrats and gave the impression of being a middle-class tourist. On her return to Canada after the first trip, Pollack was offered the position of Executive Director of the Canadian Association for Ethiopian Jews (CAEJ). She realized that if she wanted to continue her rescue and relief efforts, she would need help from the AAEJ, since the CAEJ did not have the resources for such a tremendous undertaking. She sought advice from LaDena Schnapper and Michael Winn. On her fourth trip to Ethiopia, Pollack was accompanied by three physicians who successfully treated nearly 300 persons in six villages.32
    After the 1984-85 rescue missions from Sudan, Susan Pollack moved back to the United States. In 1985, Lenhoff had hired Pollack and found out right away that she was aggressive, creative and a good fundraiser. These traits contributed to Pollack's success in rescuing the Ethiopian Jews. She continued her speaking, fundraising, and missions to Ethiopia and Israel. Pollack also organized the first AAEJ committee for fundraising.
    The series consists of subject files arranged alphabetically. Topics of potential interest to researchers of Ethiopian Jewry include absorption (Box 152, Folder 13), Black Hebrews (Box 153, Folder 7), Falas Mora (Box 154, Folder 4), famine (Box 154, Folder 5), Jewish Agency for Israel (Box 154, Folder 11), files of Susan Pollack (Box 155, Folder 9), rescues (Box 152, Folder 2), San Diego rescue (Box 156, Folder 5), summer camps (Box 156, Folder 11 and Box 157, Folder 1) and Susan Pollack Schechtman tour of Ethiopia (Box 157, Folder 2).
    - AAEJ Activist Manual, 1991 (Box 152, Folder 8)
    - AAEJ Board Materials (?), undated, 1989-1991 (Box 152, Folder 9)
    - AAEJ Board Meeting, 1991 (Box 152, Folder 10)
    - AAEJ Board Meeting and Gala Fundraiser, 1992 (Box 152, Folder 11)
    - AAEJ letter writing to Israeli officials, undated (Box 152, Folder 12)
    - Absorption, undated, 1984-1989 (Box 152, Folder 13)
    - Adas Israel Congregation, undated, 1989-1991 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Africa Watch, 1990 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - AMIT, 1991 (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - Artwork (for cards, brochures), undated, 1984, 1989, 1991-1992 (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - Baskets, undated, 1990, 1992 (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - Bibliography of Articles on Ethiopian Jews, 1985-1986 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Black Hebrews, undated, 1984-1987, 1989 (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - B'nai B'rith Youth (contains photographs), undated, 1992-1993 (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Budget, January-February 1988 (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - CNN, 1989 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - Defending Jewishness of Ethiopian Jewry, undated, 1979, 1987-1988 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - Ethiopia Faxes, undated, 1990-1992 (Box 153, Folder 12)
    - Ethiopian Jewry Books/Films/Videos, undated, 1982, 1984-1986, 1989, 1991 (Box 153, Folder 13)
    - Ethiopian Jewry Books/Films/Videos - "Unfinished Exodus", undated, 1986-1988 (Box 153, Folder 14)
    - Ethiopian Jewry Museum Exhibit, undated, 1985-1989, 1991 (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Ethiopian Jewry Trip Reports, undated, 1985-1986, 1991 (Box 154, Folder 2)
    - Ethiopian Jewry Village Maps, undated (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Falas Mora, June 1992 (Box 154, Folder 4)
    - Famine, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 154, Folder 5)
    - Foundations, undated, 1984-1987 (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Fund Raising, undated, 1984-1989 (Box 154, Folder 7)
    - General Files, undated, 1989-1992 (Box 154, Folder 8)
    - Hebrew-Amharic Dictionary, 1985 (Box 154, Folder 9)
    - High Holidays, undated, 1984, 1988 (Box 154, Folder 10)
    - Jewish Agency for Israel, 1990 (Box 154, Folder 11)
    - Letters from Ethiopian Jews, undated, 1984-1988, 1991-1992 (Box 154, Folder 12)
    - Letters from Ethiopian Jews -- Thank You AAEJ, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 155, Folder 1)
    - Op-Ed, undated, 1988 (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - Operation Moses -- Tudor Parfitt, undated, 1985-1986 (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - Oppressed Jewry, undated, 1983-1988 (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Original Camp Kit, undated, 1989 (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - Orthodox letter, 1991 (Box 155, Folder 6)
    - Plane, 1991, 1995 (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - Plays, undated (Box 155, Folder 8)
    - Pollack, Susan, undated, 1988-1992 (Box 155, Folder 9)
    - Prayers, undated, 1982, 1984, 1987-1992 (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - Press Clippings, undated, 1987, 1989 (Box 155, Folder 11)
    - Prisoners, undated, 1987-1989 (Box 155, Folder 12)
    - Program - EJ Books, undated, 1985-1986, 1988-1989 (Box 155, Folder 13)
    - Recipes, undated (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Rescues, 1986-1990 (Box 156, Folder 2)
    - Research Proposals, undated, 1988-1989, 1991 (Box 156, Folder 3)
    - Rosh Hashanah, undated, 1986, 1988 (Box 156, Folder 4)
    - San Diego Rescue, 1990 (Box 156, Folder 5)
    - Scholarships, 1981, 1984-1986 (Box 156, Folder 6)
    - Shabbat, undated, 1984-1985, 1989 (Box 156, Folder 7)
    - Sign Packet, undated, 1989 (Box 156, Folder 8)
    - Social Responsibility, undated, 1986 (Box 156, Folder 9)
    - Speeches, undated, 1989, 1992 (Box 156, Folder 10)
    - Summer Camp, undated, 1982-1983, 1988-1989 (Box 156, Folder 11)
    - Summer Camps, undated, 1986-1989 (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - Susan Schechtman Tour, undated, 1988-1991 (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - Synagogue Newsletters, undated, 1981-1985, 1987, 1989-1991 (Box 157, Folder 3)
    - World Bank, 1991-1992 (Box 157, Folder 4)
  - Series F: Articles and Reports on Ethiopian Jewry, undated, 1967, 1974-1975, 1977-1985, 1987-1991; Box 158 -- Box 159, Folder 12.
    The series contains articles and reports on Ethiopian Jewry arranged chronologically for better access, dating from 1967 to 1991.
    - "Israel and Africa: A Selected Bibliography," by Samuel Decalo, 1967 (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - "Without Cloak or Dagger: The Truth about the New Espionage," by Miles Copeland, 1974 (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - "Index Africanus," by J.O. Asamani, 1975 (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - "Sub-Saharan Africa - A Guide to Information Sources", 1977 (Box 158, Folder 4)
    - "A Cry for Jewish Education: The Falasha Jews of Ethiopia", Fall 1978 (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - Review of "Northeast Africana: A Review Article", [1979] (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - "The Falashas: A Bibliography," by Beverly Gherman, April 10, 1979 (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - "The Falashas: History and Analysis of Policy," Perspectives, April 1980 (Box 158, Folder 8)
    - "Transportation in East Africa: A Bibliography," by Daniel C. Krumes, June 1980 (Box 158, Folder 9)
    - "A Bibliography of Refugees", October-November 1980 (Box 158, Folder 10)
    - "Commonly Used Abbreviations and Acronyms," African International Relations: An Annotated Bibliography, 1981 (Box 158, Folder 11)
    - Review of "A Soviet View of Africa. An Annotated Bibliography of Ethiopia, Somalia, and Djibouti", 1981 (Box 158, Folder 12)
    - "Southern Africa and the Horn: Recent Books," Africa Today, 1981 (Box 158, Folder 13)
    - Keeping Posted, February 1981 (Box 158, Folder 14)
    - "Africa: Bibliography," San Francisco State University, 1982 (Box 158, Folder 15)
    - "An Africanist Directory", 1982 (Box 158, Folder 16)
    - Living - The Sun Times, 1982 (Box 158, Folder 17)
    - Postcards, Holocaust Flyer, undated, 1982 (Box 158, Folder 18)
    - "Seventh International Conference on Ethiopian Studies - Program," Northeast African Studies, 1982 (Box 158, Folder 19)
    - The Abstracts Journal of the African Studies Centre Leiden, vol. 13, nos. 2 and 3, 1982 (Box 158, Folder 20)
    - "Biographies of Sudanese Leaders", 1983 (Box 158, Folder 21)
    - East Africa, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 22)
    - "Horn of Africa Data Sources", 1983 (Box 158, Folder 23)
    - JTA dispatch is last effort in the campaign to stall Falashas rescue, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 24)
    - Letter from ATLIT, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 25)
    - "The Puzzle Palace: A Report on America's Most Secret Agency," by James Bamford, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 26)
    - "UJA and Falashas;" "Ethiopian Jewry;" "Books, religious articles needed by Falashas", 1983 (Box 158, Folder 27)
    - "Falashas cry for help!," The Jewish World (Albany, N.Y.), January 6, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 28)
    - "The Editor's Chair," The Jewish Post and Opinion, March 2, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 29)
    - "Continuity and Change in Cabinet," The Weekly Review, October 7, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 30)
    - "Rescue of Ethiopian Jews linked to U.S. foreign policy, Rep. Lantos says," Sentinel (Chicago), November 10, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 31)
    - "Israel dragged its feet on saving Ethiopian Jews," The Jewish Post and Opinion, December 1, 1983 (Box 158, Folder 32)
    - "Entrepreneurship for the Poor," by Malcolm Harper, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 33)
    - "Fears for black Jews in Ethiopia ignite dispute in American ranks", 1984 (Box 158, Folder 34)
    - "First Year in Israel" - Information booklet for Ethiopian immigrants in the Amharic language, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 35)
    - "UNHCR - 1984 Information Material" (Box 158, Folder 36)
    - "AAEJ to participate in new effort at drought, food relief," Sentinel (Chicago), January 5, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 37)
    - "Subtle attempt underway to rewrite history of efforts to save Falashas," Sentinel (Chicago), January 5, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 38)
    - "Falashas suffer in absorption muddles," The Jerusalem Post, February 10, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 39)
    - "Pro-Falasha groups do agree that Ethiopian Jews need help," JTA Daily News Bulletin, February 10, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 40)
    - "Dispute on handling of Falashas," The Jerusalem Post, February 12-18, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 41)
    - "Exodus for a Twice-Lost Tribe," New York Times, March 2, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 42)
    - "Falashas: Victims of Hold-Over Policy," Israel Today, January 31, 1984; "The Endangered Falashas," The Wall Street Journal, March 13, 1984 (Box 158, Folder 43)
    - Operation Moses - AAEJ Response, 1985 (Box 158, Folder 44)
    - Israeli Foreign Affairs, January 1985 (Box 158, Folder 45)
    - "Jews of Ethiopia: Man and Work," Convention Program 1/5/87, The Immigrants from Ethiopia ______ of the Situation and a Program of Action for the Basis of their absorbing, 1987 (Box 158, Folder 46)
    - 1988: Year in Review (Box 158, Folder 47)
    - "Topics about Family Matters of the Jews of Ethiopia," numbers 1-4, 1989-1990 (Box 158, Folder 48)
    - Report to the Annual Meeting of the Board of Governors of The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, June 1990 (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - "Estimate of Absorption Need for Anticipated 400,000 Olim, 1991", December 1990 (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - Articles, 1990-1991 (Box 159, Folder 3)
    - NIF Report, 1990-1991 (Box 159, Folder 4)
    - "Selected Data About The Students At The Practical Engineering College of Beer-Sheva 1990/91", 1991 (Box 159, Folder 5)
    - Sh'varim, August 1990, January 1991 (Box 159, Folder 6)
    - "The Absorption Process for Ethiopian Jews: An Assessment" (original and copy), June 10, 1991 (Box 159, Folder 7)
    - "The Hope" - a newspaper for Ethiopian immigrants of Israel, undated (Box 159, Folder 8)
    - "Jews leave Ethiopia in thousands", undated (Box 159, Folder 9)
    - "Program of Studies: Contents of Judaism for Ethiopian Immigrants," published by Department of Education and Culture, undated (Box 159, Folder 10)
    - A sample of letters that have been written to Prime Minister Begin, undated (Box 159, Folder 11)
    - "Share Tomorrow", undated (Box 159, Folder 12)
  - Series G: Ethiopian Jewry Publications, Pamphlets, and Books, 1960, 1968, 1974, 1976-1985, 1987-1991, 1993; Box 159, Folder 13 -- Box 162.
    The series consists of publications, pamphlets and books pertaining to Ethiopian Jewry, dating from 1960 to 1993.
    - "Catalog - The Practical Engineering College Beer Sheva", October 1984 (Box 159, Folder 13)
    - "My Personal Operation Moses," by Stuart Leeder, April 1985 (Box 159, Folder 14)
    - "Higher Education in Israel - A Guide for Overseas Students", 1987 (Box 159, Folder 15)
    - "An Operational Guide for Micro-Enterprise Projects", 1988 (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - "Jews of Ethiopia in Israel - Family Portraits: A Multi-faceted View," by Tzili Dolb-Gondelman, 1989 (Box 160, Folder 2)
    - "A ___ evaluation for the program of "Beta Israel" - A Program of Studies for Immigrant Children from Ethiopia," by Chagit Aharonoff, 1989 (Box 160, Folder 3)
    - "Vocational Absorption of Ethiopian Immigrants 1984-1987", February 1989 (Box 160, Folder 4)
    - "______ for the absorbing of Ethiopian immigrants ___ ____," by Edna Angel, 1990 (Box 160, Folder 5)
    - "Statistical Abstract of Israel 1990" (Box 160, Folder 6)
    - "Uprooted Children - ________ accepted/authoritative on the situation of the uprooted Jewish children in Addis Ababa - Summaries of the investigations of the occupational delegations 10/15/90-11/6/90," by Gadi Ben Ezer, Dr. Chaim Perry, 1990 (Box 160, Folder 7)
    - "Topics about the Orthodox Tradition of Jews of Ethiopia in Israel - A Guide for Teachers," by Dr. Shalva Weil, 1991 (Box 160, Folder 8)
    - African Development Information Association, USA Bulletin, September/October 1981 (Box 161, Folder 1)
    - AF: Log II - African Affairs in Washington, D.C., 1980-1981 (Box 161, Folder 2)
    - Horn of Africa, 1981-1982 (Box 161, Folder 3)
    - Letters from Exile, 1982-1984 (Box 161, Folder 4)
    - National Geographic: "Ethiopia - Revolution in the Ancient Empire", May 1993 (Box 161, Folder 5)
    - Summarised Readings in Geography 101 - Introduction to Geography of Ethiopia, Department of Geography, College of Social Sciences, Addis Ababa University, December 1981 (Box 161, Folder 6)
    - African Refugees: A Guide to Contemporary Information Sources, 1983 (Box 161)
    - Eritrea and Ethiopia in the Context of the Red Sea and Africa, by Zewde Gabre-Sellassie, March 1976 (Box 161)
    - Historical Dictionary of Ethiopia, by Chris Prouty and Eugene Rosenfeld, 1981 (Box 161)
    - The Civilizing Mission: A History of the Italo-Ethiopian War of 1935-1936, by A.J. Barker, 1968 (Box 162)
    - Bibliography on Eritrea, 1982 (Box 162)
    - Egypt's Imperial Aspirations over Lake Tana and the Blue Nile, Wondimneh Tilahun, 1979 (Box 162)
    - Ethiopia: A Country Study, edited by Harold D. Nelson and Irving Kaplan, 1981 (Box 162)
    - Greater Ethiopia: The Evolution of a Multiethnic Society, by Donald N. Levine, 1974 (Box 162)
    - The White Nile, by Alan Moorehead, 1960 (Box 162)
    - The Wilson Quarterly, Winter 1984 (Box 162)
    - Black Jews in America: A Documentary with Commentary, by Graenum Berger (IN ALEPH), 1978 (Box 162)
    - In Search for Rachamim, by Arnold Sherman (IN ALEPH), 1977 (Box 162)
    - To Serve, To Teach, To Leave, by Moshe Decter (IN ALEPH), 1977 (Box 162)
  - Series H: Card Files on Ethiopian Jews in U.S., Canada and Israel, undated, 1989-1990; Card File Boxes 163-167.
    The series consists of five card file boxes. The first four boxes contain names of Ethiopians in the U.S., Canada and Israel. The last card file box contains U.S. Postal Service return receipts dated from 1989 to 1990.
    - Ethiopians in the U.S., Canada, and Israel (4 index file boxes, unsorted), undated (Box 163-166)
    - U.S. Postal Service Return Receipts (1 index file box, unsorted), 1989-1990 (Box 167)
- Subgroup IV: Israel - Secondary Articles, undated, 1972-1992; Boxes 168-170.
  This subgroup contains secondary articles about Israel, aliyah records and family reunification records.
  - Series A: Israel, undated, 1981-1992; Box 168.
    The series contains files about Israel, absorption in Israel, the Israel Center for Ethiopian Jewry, the Ethiopian Vigil in summer of 1987, Ethiopia famine aid, Ethiopians in Israel, the Israel Free Loan Association, and Prime Minister Shamir.
    - Israel, undated, 1989-1991 (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Israel: Absorption, undated, 1982, 1984-1987 (Box 168, Folder 2)
    - Israel: Africa, undated, 1986, 1988-1989 (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - Israel Center for Ethiopian Jewry, 1990 (Box 168, Folder 4)
    - Israel, Church and State in, 1985 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - Israel: EJ Vigil: Summer 1987, undated, 1987 (Box 168, Folder 6)
    - Israel: Ethiopia Famine Aid, 1984-1986 (Box 168, Folder 7)
    - Israel: Ethiopians in Israel (see OS6F Folder 1), undated, 1981, 1983-1989, 1991 (Box 168, Folder 8)
    - Israel Free Loan Association, undated, 1992 (Box 168, Folder 9)
    - Israel: Prime Minister Shamir, 1987, 1989 (Box 168, Folder 10)
  - Series B: Aliyah Records, undated, 1984-1989; Box 169, Folders 1-17.
    The series contains the aliyah records of individuals, placed into folders alphabetically by last name. The records date from 1984 to 1989.
    - Aliyah: A, undated, 1984-1989 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Aliyah: B, 1985-1988 (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - Aliyah: C, 1987 (Box 169, Folder 3)
    - Aliyah: D, 1984-1989 (Box 169, Folder 4)
    - Aliyah: E, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 5)
    - Aliyah: F, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 6)
    - Aliyah: G, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 7)
    - Aliyah: H, 1985-1986 (Box 169, Folder 8)
    - Aliyah: K, 1986-1989 (Box 169, Folder 9)
    - Aliyah: L, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 10)
    - Aliyah: M, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 11)
    - Aliyah: N, 1985-1988 (Box 169, Folder 12)
    - Aliyah: R, 1989 (Box 169, Folder 13)
    - Aliyah: S, 1984-1988 (Box 169, Folder 14)
    - Aliyah: T, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 15)
    - Aliyah: W, 1986-1989 (Box 169, Folder 16)
    - Aliyah: Y-Z, 1985-1989 (Box 169, Folder 17)
  - Series C: Family Reunification Records, undated, 1972-1990; Box 169, Folder 18 -- Box 170.
    The series contains the reunification records of families arranged alphabetically by last name, dating from 1972 to 1990. The series also contains reunification records of families in the Sudan, as well as Non-Jews and AAEJ family reunification names/numbers.
    - Family Reunification, undated (Box 169, Folder 18)
    - Family Reunification Records: A, undated, 1984-1990 (Box 169, Folder 19)
    - Family Reunification Records: B, undated, 1984-1990 (Box 169, Folder 20)